(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T02:06:30.378417",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
開演まで今しばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援OKです
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is okay.
ライブグッズ 2次販売決定！！
11.19 公演終了後〜
Second round of concert goods sales confirmed!
Starting after the performance on Nov. 19
どアニメ宣言！
Do-Anime Sengen!
アニメにハマって
I got hooked on anime,
歌いたくなっちゃった
and now I want to sing!
推しのシーン見ながらカラオケ歌えるなんて
Singing karaoke while watching my favorite scenes...
尊すぎて 辛い！
...is so precious, it hurts!
歌いたい曲見つけよう！
Find the song you want to sing!
JOYSOUND!
ねえ、今日はどこ行く？
Hey, where are we going today?
Yahoo!カーナビ「推しドラ」好評販売中！
Yahoo! Car Navi "Oshidora" is now on sale!
今ならダブル購入で、兎田ぺこらとの限定ボイスも聞けちゃう！
Buy both now to hear exclusive voice lines with Usada Pekora!
AZKiと一緒にドライブしよう！
Let's go for a drive with AZKi!
「推しドラ」で検索！
Search for "Oshidora"!
AZKi holoplus JACK / ホロプラス ジャック中
[AZKi holoplus JACK / Currently hijacking holoplus]
開演までしばらくお待ちください
[The concert will be starting soon]
Attention / ご来場のお客様へ
[Attention / To all attendees]
ライブグッズ 2次販売決定!!
[Concert Merchandise: Second round of sales confirmed!]
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください／声出し応援OKです
Attention to all visitors:
Please be aware of flashing lights. Cheering loudly is OK!
ライブグッズ 2次販売決定!!
11.19 公演終了後〜
Live goods second round sales decided!
Available on Nov 19th after the performance.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
[The concert will be starting soon]
照明の点滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援OKです
[Attention: Please be aware of flashing lights / Cheering loudly is OK]
ライブグッズ 2次販売決定!! 11.19 公演終了後〜
[Live Goods: 2nd round of sales confirmed! Available after the 11/19 concert~]
本日は AZKiソロライブ 2025「Departure」に
Today, to AZKi Solo Live 2025 "Departure,"
ご来場いただき ありがとうございます！
thank you so much for coming!
こんこんこん、こあずき！
Kon-kon-kon, Ko-AZKi!
あ、みんな元気がいいですね！
Oh, everyone is in high spirits!
右手にマイク、左手に地図
Microphone in my right hand, map in my left hand...
あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー、AZKiです！
Geolocating your heart, I'm AZKi!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために
To ensure everyone enjoys the live show until the end,
いくつかご案内させていただきます
I have a few announcements to make.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は
During the performance, photographing, recording,
固くお断りいたします
and filming are strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております
Smoking is prohibited inside the venue.
喫煙はご遠慮ください
Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は
In the unlikely event that you feel unwell,
無理をせず、近くのスタッフへお知らせください
please don't push yourself and let a nearby staff member know.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ
Moshing, diving within the venue,
ステージに物を投げ込むなど
or throwing things onto the stage,
他の皆の迷惑になったり
and any acts that cause trouble for others
公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です
or disrupt the performance are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってください！
Please follow the rules and have a blast!
えらい！
Good job!
また、本公演は映像配信および
Also, for this performance, cameras for video streaming
写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り
and photography are present inside the venue,
客席が映り込む場合があります保存
and the audience seating may be captured.
これらの映像や写真は、プロモーションなどに
These videos and photos may be used
使用される可能性がありますので
for promotional purposes,
あらかじめご了承ください
so please be aware of this in advance.
はーい！えらい！
Yes! Good job!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは
Also, the hashtag for the live show is...
「#AZKiと未来へ」です
"#AZKiと未来へ" (Into the future with AZKi).
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてくれると嬉しい！
I'd be so happy if you post a lot using the hashtag!
お願いします！
Please do!
それでは、開演までもう少しです
Now, there are just a few moments left until the show starts.
みんなの声、いっぱい聞かせてくれー！
Let me hear your voices loud and clear!
もっと
More...
もっと...
Even more...
鏡よ 教えて
Mirror, mirror, please tell me,
私の...
where my...
私は どこにあるのだろう
Where am I supposed to be?
わからない わからないよ
I don't know, I just don't know
周りと比べたってさ 虚しくなるだけ
Comparing myself to others only leaves me feeling empty
あのノイズが海鳴りのように 涙を奪う
That noise steals my tears like the roaring of the sea
切り取った風景を道標にしよう そうだ
Let's use this captured scenery as a guidepost, yes
傷ついた感情も連れて行くから
Because I'll bring along even my wounded emotions
そっと響くカンパニュラが 新しい未来を感じてる
The softly echoing campanula feels a new future
怖くたって 進むしかないでしょう
Even if I'm scared, I have no choice but to move forward, right?
どこまでも
No matter how far
届けこの祈りよ 光となれ
May this prayer reach out and turn into light
もっと もっと
More, more
少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
Even if it's step by step, the answer that is myself...
もっと
...more...
...more!
教えて 私の証は
Tell me, is the proof of my existence...
輝けているのだろうか
...shining brightly?
見つけたい 見つけたいよ
I want to find it, I really want to find it
誰かの決められる輪は 苦しくなるだけ
The boundaries set by others only make it painful
あのノイズも力に変えるよ 心に誓う
I swear to my heart I will turn even that noise into strength
錆びついた運命の歯車を回そう ほら
Let's spin the rusted gears of fate, look
着飾った感情を脱ぎ捨てるから
Because I'll cast away my dressed-up emotions
そっと紡ぐ栞は 叶えたい願いを信じてる
The bookmark softly spun believes in the wish I want to come true
胸を張って 歌うしかないでしょう
Be proud and stand tall, I have no choice but to sing, right?
全力で
With all my might
気が遠くなるような 歌に変わる日まで
Until the day it turns into an overwhelming song
もっと
More...
...more!
泣き濡れながらでいい
Even if I'm soaked in tears...
全てが宝物
...everything is a treasure!
リアルライブ！今日も楽しんでいってね！
Live concert! Keep having fun today!
いつの日かこの声を 受け取ってくれたなら
If someday you receive this voice of mine...
この言葉を君に
...then these words are for you
もう大丈夫 一人じゃない
It's okay now, you are not alone
強い想いを 繋ぐよ
I will connect our strong feelings
一歩踏み出してみた
I tried taking a step forward
優しく世界は微笑む
And the world smiled gently
高鳴る気持ちに身を任せて さあ行こう
Leaving myself to my pounding heart, let's go!
そっと響くカンパニュラが 新しい未来を感じてる
The softly echoing campanula feels a new future
怖くたって 進むしかないでしょう
Even if I'm scared, I have no choice but to move forward, right?
どこまでも
No matter how far
届けこの祈りよ 光となれ
May this prayer reach out and turn into light
もっと もっと
More, more
少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
Even if it's step by step, the answer that is myself...
もっと
...more...
...more!
この扉の向こうが
If beyond this door...
未開の可能性なら 今、思いを動かせるの
...lies unexplored potential, I can move my thoughts now
暗闇を手探りで 不安と焦燥の中
Groping in the dark, amidst anxiety and frustration...
こぼれる光を見た
...I saw a spilling light
手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand
この先は君と
From here on, with you
なものだから
...because we are.
遠きを乞うて
I pray for the distant future,
繋がるよ 心が今
our hearts are connecting now.
そう
Yes,
創造するの 私のストーリー
I will create my own story,
もっと聞かせて 君を知りたいから
tell me more, because I want to know you.
輝かせよう 新しい世界
Let's make this new world shine,
生まれる意味を見つけるのさ
we will find the meaning of our birth.
全てが始まるこの場所で
In this place where everything begins,
声が枯れるまで叫んで
I will scream until my voice runs dry.
答え教えてよ
Tell me the answer,
Dear Melancholy
Yeah!
体と感情が交差する
My body and emotions intersect,
ただ、知る、自分は何？
simply searching, who am I?
0と1を繋いで交差する
Connecting 0 and 1, they intersect,
世界は1つじゃない
the world is not just one.
インプットとアウトプットの数式 増えていく
The formulas of inputs and outputs keep increasing,
盲目に正論振りかざして首を絞める
blindly brandishing righteousness, choking myself.
私の生きる世界は
The world I live in,
自分の手で選ばせてよ
let me choose it with my own hands.
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity,
この身が、この辺が、痛いよ
this body, this part here, it hurts.
上っ面の慰め通り 収束していく可愛いフェイク
Just like superficial consolation, converging into a cute fake,
私は私は誰かにとって
will I, will I, for someone else,
代わるの？
be replaced?
どんどん行くよ！ みんなペンライト振ってね！
Here we go! Everyone, wave your penlights!
どうして気付いてしまったの
Why did I end up realizing it?
熱くなるほどに隠しきれない戸惑い
A confusion I cannot hide, growing hotter,
ぎこちない二人
the awkward pair,
危うい眼差し
and fragile glances.
揺れる心バレないように
So my swaying heart won't be found out,
人知れず
secretly,
響く胸の鼓動
my heartbeat echoes.
呼吸さえままならないのに
Even though I can barely breathe,
きっとどこかで願っているんだ
surely somewhere, I am wishing for
終わりのない時間を
a time that never ends.
恋の始まりは誰も知らない 私だけの宝物
No one knows the beginning of love, my own secret treasure.
少しでも言葉が交わされたら
If even a few words were exchanged,
陽だまりのような笑顔
your sun-like smile,
土砂降りの泣き顔も全部
and your tearful face like a downpour, everything
失くしてしまいそうで
feels like it might be lost.
もしも一つだけ叶うのならば
If only one wish could come true,
ただ君のすぐ隣で
I just want to be right by your side,
過ぎてゆく季節眺めていたい
watching the passing seasons together.
溢れそうなほどの思いは
These overflowing feelings,
胸の奥に仕舞い込んだ
I locked deep inside my heart.
二人の声が空に
Our voices are being sucked
吸い込まれていく
into the sky.
閉ざした世界 微かに聞こえる音
A closed world, a faintly heard sound,
世界で二人 切り取ったラスト
the ending we carved out, just the two of us in this world.
届きそうで すれ違った心が
Our hearts, seeming so close yet passing by each other,
ちょっと痛んだ
hurt a little.
ここで待って
Wait here,
wait here,
ここで待って
wait here.
決められないままで
Remaining unable to decide,
戸惑い溢れてしまうよ
my confusion is overflowing.
もう何度も
Already, so many times,
繰り返した
we repeated it.
こぼれた想いを
Count up the spilled thoughts...
数えて
...one by one.
何度も
Again and again,
繰り返した
I repeated it.
世界
A world...
...a world...
開くのを待っている
...that is waiting to open.
まだまだ盛り上がっていくよー！
We're going to keep hyping it up!
もっと声出せるよねー！
I know you can make even more noise!
ばかばかしいな
How ridiculous,
不自由な思考
this restricted way of thinking.
意味がないなら 楽しい歌を
If there's no meaning to it, then let's sing a fun song.
攻めてく人 逃げてく人
Those who attack, those who run away...
良くない人に 生きる資格
Do bad people even have the right...
ない
...to live?
前向きな夕暮れ
An optimistic twilight.
狂った世界で僕らはみんな生きてるから
Because we're all living in this crazy world,
好きになったり 憎んでしまったりする
we fall in love, and we end up hating.
飾る手 祈りのように
Hands adorned, as if in prayer.
ニュースが流れた大事件に
At a major incident reported on the news,
涙を流す人はいない
there's no one shedding any tears.
ビルボードが嘘の街
The billboards of this town of lies,
さあ 抜け出して 光の街へ
come on, let's break out toward the city of light.
メドレーラスト！Fake.Fake.Fake!
The last song of the medley! Fake.Fake.Fake!
見せかけばかりすべて
It's all nothing but appearances,
上辺で飾って誤魔化して
dressed up on the surface to deceive.
何が善悪か
Not knowing what is good or evil...
分からないから壊れていく
...things are starting to break down.
一体何が本当だっけ
What on earth was the truth again?
期待しては泣き濡れて
I hope, only to end up drenched in tears.
ばかがいつも勝ってしまうよ
The fools always end up winning.
こんな異常だらけの世界で
In this world full of abnormalities,
存在意義探しているんだ
I'm searching for my reason to exist.
不本意なエリア 自由なエリア
An involuntary area, a free area...
どこですか
...where are they?
こんな異常だらけの世界で
In this world full of abnormalities,
存在意義探しているんだ
I'm searching for my reason to exist.
何を言われても
No matter what anyone says,
満たされることはないよ
I will never be satisfied.
感覚すら消えて
Even my senses fade away,
すべて忘れて
forgetting everything.
はい！
Yes!
ということで、AZKi ソロライブ 2025 「Departure」へ ようこそ！
And with that, welcome to AZKi Solo Live 2025 "Departure"!
ちょっとぶっ飛ばしすぎた...ぶっ飛ばしました。
I think I went a little too fast... I really flew through that.
あ、見渡す限り、ペンライトたくさん！
Ah, as far as the eye can see, so many penlights!
本当に冒頭からこの景色を見てもう感極まってしまっているんですが、
Honestly, seeing this view right from the start has already made me so emotional,
えー、みんな本当に今日来てくれてありがとうございます！
but... everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
えー、今日はAZKiにとって初めての アリーナでのソロライブです！
Today is AZKi's very first solo live in an arena!
この景色、本当にもう胸がいっぱいで... まだ、まだ早いか、まだ、この涙は。
Looking at this view, my heart is so full... Wait, it's still too early for these tears!
ということで、えー、みんな今日はね、えー、貴重な1日を、このAZKiのライブのために時間を作ってくれてありがとうございます！
So, everyone, thank you so much for taking the time out of your precious day for this AZKi live!
えー、早速なんですが、えー、ぶっ飛ばしましたメドレー、どうでした？
And first of all, how did you like the medley we just flew through?
ありがとうございます。そしてね、もちろん
Thank you. And of course,
1曲目は、この曲と決めていました、Creating World、ということで
I decided on this song for the first track: "Creating World".
新EPから、えーと、Restartからね、1曲お届けいたしましたが、
I delivered one song from my new EP, "Restart"...
みんな、EPは聴いてくれましたかー？
Has everyone listened to the EP yet?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そして、そして、本日の衣装、どうですか？
And also, how do you like today's outfit?
いいですか？早速ね、キービジュアルで、みんなこの衣装を着るんじゃないかと思ってたと思うんですけど、
Is it good? I think everyone expected me to wear this outfit from the key visual,
なんと、初期のAZKi...
but surprisingly, this is early AZKi's...
イメージして、黒のカラーバリエーションも作っていただきました！
They also created a black color variation based on that image!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そして！今日のね、素敵なステージでございます。
And! This is today's wonderful stage.
みんな、上部の装飾、気づきました？変化してたの気づきました？この上のね。
Did everyone notice the decorations at the top? Did you see them changing?
この、今、α（アルファ）っていう...
Right now, this "alpha" symbol...
お！動、あ！ピカピカピカピカ！
Oh! It moved... Ah! Flashing, flashing!
ありがとうございます。この変化、気づきましたでしょうか？
Thank you very much. Did you notice this change?
曲の頭で実は、あの、このアルファの装飾部分がですね、あの、色が変わってまして。
Actually, at the beginning of the song, the color of this alpha decoration changed,
ちょっと、あの、ついていくの大変だったよね。「この色にしてください！」っていう。
it was probably hard to keep up, right? Since it was saying, "Please use this color!"
ペンライトカラーになっておりました。
It matched the penlight colors.
本当に曲の冒頭の方なので、あの、見れた方は...
Since it was really at the very beginning of the song, for those who were able to see it...
ありがとう！あの、変えていただけたらなと思います。
Thank you! I hope you can change your colors to match.
それに合わせてね、みんなもペンライト点灯していただいたり、二色光った時はですね、
Accordingly, you can light up your penlights, and when it shines in two colors,
ペンライトも二色にしてください！
please change your penlights to two colors as well!
みんなで一緒に今日のライブ作っていこう！よろしくお願いします！
Let's create today's live concert together! Thank you so much!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
ということで、今日のライブはですね、バンドメンバーと一緒にお届けしております！
And so, today's live performance is brought to you with our band members!
すごい素晴らしい演奏ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for the amazing performance!
しかも、なんと！今回はですね、バイオリンも参加しております！
And what's more! This time, we also have a violin joining us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今日のために、特別にアレンジした楽曲もたくさんあるので、お楽しみに！
We have many songs specially arranged just for today, so please look forward to them!
そして今日はね、現地のみんなだけじゃなくてですね、配信で見てくれる開拓者もいます！
And today, it's not just everyone here at the venue, but we also have Pioneers watching via stream!
配信のみんなー！
To everyone on the stream!
はい、コメントも見えてるよ！うおー、いぇーい！あずきちー！ふぅ、いぇーい！
Yes, I can see your comments! Whoa, yay! Azukichi! Woo, yay!
バイオリンがすごい！
The violin is amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ということで、本日は、ハッシュタグ「#AZKiと未来へ」で、
So today, please use the hashtag #AZKiと未来へ (To the Future with AZKi) to share
今日の感想や、印象に残った瞬間を
your thoughts on today's show and your favorite moments,
ポストしてください！あとで全部見に行きます！
and post them! I'll check them all out later!
よろしくー！配信のみんな,スクショもよろしく！
Thank you! Stream viewers, feel free to take screenshots too!
そして、皆様、YouTube、TikTokでご覧の皆様...
And to everyone watching on YouTube and TikTok...
残念なお知らせ... あ、早い早い（笑）
I have a sad announce... Ah, you're reacting too fast! (laughs)
無料チラ見せはここまでー！
The free preview ends here!
えー！ありがとうございます、現地の「えー」もいただきまして。
Aww! Thank you, I appreciate the sighs of disappointment from the venue too.
まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは、概要欄の
For those who want to keep exciting this show with me,
リンクから配信サイトへ飛べますので、ここからが
you can go to the streaming site via the link in the description. Because from here,
本番なので！
the real show begins!
たくさんの方に、見ていただきたいなと思っています！
I hope many of you will join and watch!
今回のライブなんですが、これまでAZKiが歩んできた軌跡、
As for today's live concert, the path AZKi has walked so far,
そして、これから歩んでいく未来、そのすべてをみんなと一緒にひとつの物語として
and the future we will walk from now on, I want to connect all of it with everyone
繋いでいくような一日にしたいと、思っています！
into a single story today!
このライブで、私の今
With this live show, everything I am right now,
のすべてを、音楽とともに、まっすぐみんなに届けていきます！
I will deliver it all straight to you through my music!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
それでは、どんどん行きますよ！
Now, let's keep going!
最後まで一緒に楽しんでいこうね！
Let's have fun together until the very end!
一緒に歌おう！
Let's sing together!
みんなの声、聴かせて！
Let me hear your voices!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！